It's yours. Today's dinner.
What happened?
He got me good.
Are you okay?
Yeah. It'll heal right away, after all.
Whew, I'm beat.
Yeah?
Oh, he's back.
Welcome back.
How'd it go?
I went as far as I could go, but there's nothing out there.
Nothing out there?
No islands, no boats, no land masses?
Nothing man-made?
Nothing.
Just the same ocean,
extending forever in every direction.
We're not home yet.
What do you mean?
That we're still not back in our original world.
Just like when the school was enveloped in darkness,
we're in yet another world.
Yeah, we sure are.
Ms. Mizuho?
Are you in here?
Hey, I was after one of these!
What do you know, she wears makeup.
Mine now. I mean, she can order
anything she wants, regardless of price.
Even this castle.
It's been a month since we started transmitting an SOS,
but we haven't received any responses,
let alone been rescued.
We still have internet,
but all web pages are frozen.
Plus we can't send anything to the outside.
There's still the possibility that someone will come to rescue us, right?
Perhaps. But I believe there's another way to get us back.
Other worlds may provide clues for our return,
or even lead us straight home.
Not long ago, other gateways were discovered,
thanks to Nagara.
These gateways that he stumbled upon inside the school
led to various other worlds.
However, those worlds are all places that boggle the mind
and reject the presence of us humans.
How does that lead us to a way home?
Good question. First of all,
here on this island, anything that breaks
stays broken, no matter how long you wait.
But what about over at the school?
In there, if something breaks, if you wait for a little while,
it returns to normal, as if nothing happened.
As a result, we can continue to use the power and water,
and the emergency food supplies are a veritable buffet.
Also, we, along with the school, are in a state of stasis.
So even when we get hurt,
our wounds are healed before we know it.
Almost as if nothing ever happened.
Which led me to wonder—
the school and the island are totally different worlds,
and the same goes for the other new worlds that we found.
So maybe the discovery of these worlds is the same phenomenon as what made us drift in the first place.
And if we retrace that phenomenon...
Why did this drift occur?
...we'll arrive at what caused all of this?
That's correct.
And before the world sinks, at that.
Whoa! Ow!
Are you okay? Did you get burned?
No, I'm fine.
Water, somebody! Go get some water!
Oh, right!
Not this again.
Water! I brought water!
Huh? There's a hole?
I can't take this. I want to go home.
More of that blue fire, huh?
Does anyone have any idea what's causing it?
We still don't know anything about this island.
We need to ensure we take care of ourselves.
Um... Thanks.
Sure. No trouble at all.
Fugly.
What?
Uh...
The student council president was wondering if you knew
when those supplies would arrive.
Oh, looks like it'll be a little longer.
How much is a little? A day? Three days?
All right, I'll tell her it's three days.
Also, there's something else.
What?
Well, it's just...
earlier, in the woods...
What was that? I can't hear you.
Oh, it's nothing.
Okay.
Huh?
Tora? Where are you?
How did we...
get stuck doing this, anyway?
What choice did we have? There's nothing else to do.
Whoa!
Look at that!
It happened again!
It's on fire.
Man, this island must have a demon living on it!
You think that's what this is?
It sure does burn in the weirdest way, huh?
Do you think it might be someone's power?
Mizuho might know something.
Yeah? How come?
I saw her in the woods earlier,
standing in front of a burning tree.
It was this same kind of blue fire.
Are you for real?
Fire! Fire!
Rajdhani!
Are you okay?
Yeah...
Is this...
I bet Mizuho is doing this.
Huh?
I mean, everything that's burning
is stuff that Mizuho's power has produced, right?
That's true.
Now that you mention it,
those tools that started burning were also...
And you were just saying that you saw Mizuho burning a tree in the forest!
No, I said—
Huh? What's that about?
He said he saw it for himself! Mizuho gave this hard glare,
and bam! This tree just caught fire!
And it was a blue fire, at that!
No, I didn't. What I said was—
That settles it, then!
You can't tell anything by just that. We have to verify it.
I'll go tell the others.
Uh, wait...
Here.
What's this?
Info on the message board users.
Huh? How did you get this?
I asked my grandpa's lawyer,
and had him file a disclosure request.
I took a look...
and here she is, from our class.
What's up?
You have a pretty intense look on your face.
I just can't let this go.
Well, there were extenuating
circumstances—on both sides.
That's just hand-waving it.
There are times when just being right isn't always for the best.
Still... I don't like it.
In that case...
maybe it's a good thing you're still a child.
I suppose.
Tora! Where are you?! Tora!
Can we have a moment?
You're the one who's been
posting about me, aren't you?
What are you talking about?
Denying it won't help you.
We have proof that you're the one behind it.
Wow, that's the privileged class for you.
You operate differently, all right.
Retract what you said, right now!
Why?
It's the truth, isn't it?
What's wrong with stating facts?
Huh? How can you shrug this off?!
I wonder if he knows that you used the library's Wi-Fi
to slander one of your fellow students.
He has nothing to do with this.
You say that—but as a teacher, he's still liable.
Why don't you apologize to the student council president?
—t up...
What's that? I can't hear you.
I didn't do anything wrong. You apologize to everyone!
Are you...
What's this? Those blue fires are Mizuho's power?
Yeah, I heard it was a curse she invoked.
None of us understand what she's thinking.
It's scary.
Whatcha up to?
It's too late.
There's... nothing we can do.
This is the same as the first day.
What do you mean?
That day, when we first started drifting,
you left another bird to die.
Well, I was in a hurry...
Besides, they say it's not good to do anything if you don't know what you're doing.
So?
You're right. I just let it die
because I'm a heartless person.
Is that what you want to hear?
That's not true.
What do you know? You talk like you know everything.
I didn't say anything then...
but is being abandoned by someone
any reason for abandoning someone else?
Hey.
Good to see you.
We have a question for you. Would you mind?
Are you behind the blue fires?
That's ridiculous.
I'm only asking this for your sake.
To give you a chance to earn back our trust—
Huh?!
Look, we don't want you to have a repeat of the mishap with Cap.
Don't you group me in with that brute!
I'm sick and tired of your lies!
Why won't you understand?
We just want to protect you, that's all.
Unless you change your ways,
that's what's going to happen.
Did you figure anything out?
Hey, perfect timing.
What's this?
That there's a "PocketGame".
It's a portable game device from way back.
I got it from Mizuho in exchange for some toys I made for her.
It's the only thing that didn't burn up in the fire earlier,
which intrigued me, and got me thinking.
What's the difference between what burned,
and what didn't burn?
Hmm... So what is it?
It's probably whether it was traded for, or taken.
Huh?
This was something that was exchanged in a fair trade between Mizuho and me,
but the rest of it was stuff I got from Mizuho without compensation.
You're talking cash, right?
That's right.
Ah, yes. How would you like this special item?
Huh? You're asking me now?
Come on, just take it.
Okay...
O-Ow, hot...
It's all right.
This fire just feels hot—it doesn't do us any harm.
You're right.
And so, Mizuho's things aren't all that burn.
I made that toy using my power.
So...
the fires aren't Mizuho's fault after all, huh?
No.
So is this another of this world's rules?
Most likely.
There are still many unknown elements in play,
and I can't say anything for certain.
Then again...
I'd say I've deduced that Mizuho isn't the culprit here.
But even still, I wish she would come out and say so herself.
We're all too dependent.
Both on her, and on this world.
Tora!
Are you back yet? Hello?
Hey!
That's Tora's dish.
He...
still doesn't know anything.
He can't live on his own yet.
Just like me...
If you'll just show sincere remorse
and offer an apology for everything you've done up to now,
we will forgive you.
Why don't we all work together to rise above this difficult situation?
We'll give you until noon tomorrow. Think about it.
What did you see earlier?
You're going to lose someone dear to you again by doing this.
It's such a simple thing. Just one phrase.
I know that!
If you'd just said it,
you wouldn't have lost him.
Come on, you gotta be quick before it's all gone!
Nah, I'm good. You can have this one too.
Huh? You sure?
Yeah. There isn't really anything I want anyway.
Thanks! You're a great guy, huh?
Oh, and no take backs—
Ow!
My money!
Hot! Hot!
Mizuho is behind this!
We should get rid of her!
I'm telling you, she isn't the one doing this!
These fires are part of the island's rules,
and if we pay for things, they won't burn up!
In any case, we have to do
something about this, and fast.
That's Mizuho's cat.
Yeah.
Catnapping?
No!
He's hurt, and in bad shape.
Oh yeah? And what have you done with the real Nagara?
It's my fault that everyone is distrustful of Mizuho.
Let's go.
Huh?
Let's take him back to Mizuho.
How do we do that?
We run.
Fast as we can.
They're all a bunch of liars.
There she is!
Ow!
Um...
It's all my fault...
that everyone is blaming you.
Because I said something misleading, they all...
Not really. They would have started to blame me sooner or later.
Even so...
I'm sorry.
Oh yeah...
Your cat was in the woods, unable to move.
Thank goodness.
Hey, so how long are you planning on sulking?
You're not burning everything, right?
Why don't you speak up already and—
I know! I've known I should since all this started!
It's just that there wasn't
anything I could do by myself.
Well, we can't live here anymore, can we?
It turns out...
we aren't able to change the world after all.
So it's okay.
Yeah.
The island's gone back to the way it was before?
What's going on here?
Awesome! Leave it to Asakaze!
All the fires...
were not caused by me.
Although...
I was the one who made it rain money,
and set the island on fire.
Huh? You were?
Are you serious?!
So for that much, at least, I'll apologize. I'm sorry.
But...
the rest of it isn't my fault, okay? Absolutely not!
So let's review...
What happens if you get something on this island without paying for it?
Ow!
It burns up. We don't know why.
But as long as that's the way it works,
Hey...
we have to accept it, and live with it.
So today, I'm announcing a revolutionary new app,
which will allow us to adapt to life in this world.
Hyo-ryu-coin!
This is an electronic payment service
that allows you to create ledgers,
and make asset transactions over the internet.
By using this, we won't be
transgressing the island's rules.
We'll be able to exchange goods without having them catch fire.
Here, for you.
Why?
To thank you for saving my cat.
U-Um,
we have to settle it. How much?
Nothing.
It's a present, after all.
So what do we do now?
I wasn't expecting this world to go back to the way it was, too.
I, uh...
I can see the way out.
Huh? Just like...
Yeah. The place we're supposed to go home to.
I thought I could just about reach out and touch it...
but right now, it's just a pinpoint, far away.
"Compass". That's my power.